A Guide to the American International Association for Economic and Social Development (AIA) records FA079
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Publications and Miscellaneous, Undated; 3
  - Inter-American Council on Nutrition Education (CIDEA) - Publications #6-8a (Box 67, Folder 471)
    6) Estas Cifra son Una Campanada de Alarma. (3 copies) 7) Al Servico del Pueblo Venezolano. (3 copies) 8a) "El Mercado Libre." (Cuaderno 9). 1952.
  - Inter-American Council on Nutrition Education (CIDEA) - Publication #9 - "Lo Que Comemos en Casa." (Cuaderno 13). 1952 (Box 67, Folder 472)
  - Inter-American Council on Nutrition Education (CIDEA) - Publications #10-13 (Box 68, Folder 473)
    10) "La Ratoncita Margarita." (3 copies) 11) "Aventuras de Mediecito." (3 copies) 12a-b) "Titirifi, El Perrito de Circo." (3 copies) 13 a-k) "Las Aventuras de Juancito Salud." (series of ten comic books) (3 copies each a-j)
  - Inter-American Council on Nutrition Education (CIDEA) - Publications #14-46 (Box 68, Folder 474)
    14) "Qué Es Alimentación?" (3 copies) 15) "Tu Salud Depende de Una Alimentación Equilibrada." (3 copies) 16) "No Le Tengas Miedo a Las Comidas Livianas" 17) Vida Larga Sana y Feliz. (2 copies) 18a-b) "La Leche Alimenta Tanto Que Siempre Resulta Barota." 19) "Platos Criollos Sabrosos y Nutritivos." (3 copies) 20) "A Falta de Carne - Coma Huevos." (3 copies) 21) "Si No Hat Carne - Coma Pescado." (3 copies) 23) El Banquete de los Animales, Juegos de CIDEA. 24) Mi Registro de Buera Alimentación. 25) Si Ud. Quiere Que su Nino Coma. (3 copies) 26) El Queso Puede Sustituir a La Carne. (2 copies) 27) Tome Leche y Tendra Buenos Dientes y Huesos fuertes. 28) La Leche le Hara Crecer Sano, Cuide el Desarrollo de sus Hijos Dandoles Tres Vasos de Leche al Dia. 29) Las Ensaladas son le Mejor fuente de Vitaminas. 30) Las Frutas Frescas Criollas Son Mas Ricas en Vitaminas. 31) Fortifiquese! Coma Carne Pescado y Huevos. 32) La Leche. 33) Tu Energia Depende de lo Que Comes. (3 copies) 34) Cuidado! Puede Haber una Bomba de Tiempo en tu Comida. (3 copies) 35) Guieres Comer Bien? (2 copies) 36) Amigo de Panchito! Conoces los 7 Grupose Basicos de Alimentos? (2 copies) 37) Alimentos Que su Nino Necesita 38) Alimentación Infantil 1 a 3 Anos. (2 copies) 39) Que Cuesta Poco y Vale Mucho? 40) Alimentos Que Dan Fuerza. 41) Los Amigos de Panchito Comen Frutas Criollas Todos los Dias. 42) No de los Conejos Mejores Alimentos Que a Sus Familiares. 43) No le Tengas Miedo a Las Comidas Livianas. 44) Comida Balanceada para 7 Dias. 45a-d) Four Napkins with slogans. 46) La Hoja del Hogar.
  - Inter-American Council on Nutrition Education (CIDEA) - Publications #47-78 (Box 68, Folder 475)
    47) "No Abra La Puerta a La Tuberculosis." (Describes tuberculosis and its prevention) 48) "Confesiones de una Mosca. (Flies as disease carriers) (2 copies) 49) "Educación Higiénica del Niño." (Simple rules for better health) (3 copies) 50) "Anquilostomo." (Hookworm and its control) 51) Unicinariasis. 52) Come Usted Para Estar Sano? O Para Enfermarse? 53) La Salud Se Compra Con Limpieza. 53.3) Annual pictoral kitchen calendar with recipes using local foods. 1953. 53.5) Annual pictoral kitchen calendar with recipes using local foods. 1954. (3 copies) 54) Annual pictoral kitchen calendar with recipes using local foods. 1955. (3 copies) 55) Annual pictoral kitchen calendar with recipes using local foods. 1956. (2 copies) 56a-f) Monthly pamphlets of menus using local foods available at the time. Issued over a period of several years. 57) "La Vie de 'Chico' Carrasquel." (baseball hero) (3 copies) 58) "Luis Sánchez 'Diamante Negro'." (Venezuelan bullfighter) (3 copies) 59) "Carmen Guevara ''Doña Bárbara'." (lady automobile racing driver) 60) "Alimentos Protectores de Su Salud." 61) "Alimentos Constructores y Energécticos." (3 copies) 62) "Las Vitaminas y Los Minerales Son Imprescindibles Para Su Salud." (2 copies) 63) El Hidago Es Un Alimento Muy Rico. 64a-b) El Equilibrio de tu Salud Depende de Una Buena Alimentacion (3 copies of a) 65) Pobre Juan. (3 copies) 66) Ahorrar en comida ed gastar en botica y en entierros. (2 copies) 67) Dime lo que Comes y te Dire Quien eres. 68) Que Necesita tu cuerpo? (2 copies) 69) Haz como Panchito. (2 copies) 70) Te gustaria que los animales fuerian los amos de tus hijos? (3 copies) 71) Si nole resulta facil comprar a qui tiene Ud. Una Lista de Compras. (2 copies) 72) Alimentate bien y gozaras de la vida. (3 copies) 73) Todos creemos saber comer. Pero, comerias gusanos o fideos com dulce de limon? (2 copies) 74) Es dificil que esto occurra... (2 copies) 75) Cuide sus dientes... (3 copies) 76) Desarrollese sano y fuerte como pescado. (3 copies) 77) Comer bien no es comer mucho. (2 copies) 78) No botes centavos... (3 copies)
  - National Agrarian Institute (IAN) - Publication #1 - Manuel de Operaciones Agricola, Caracas, 1951 (Box 68, Folder 476)
  - International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC) Research Institute - Publications #1-2 (Box 68, Folder 477)
    1) Report, November 1950 - December 1956. (3 copies) 2) Informe sobre el programa experimental de amoz Desarrollo en Venezuela en el ano 1953, William L. Crawford; November 1953.
  - Inter-American Popular Information Program (PIIP) - Publications #1-9 (Box 68, Folder 478)
    1) Adis Castro, Gonzalo, and Frederick B. Waisanen. "Place of Residence and Attitutes Toward Mental Illness." San José, Costa Rico: Center for Psychological Research of the University of Costa Rica, 1965. (Also in Spanish) 2) Anderson, H. Calvert. "The ABC Communication Team." (folder) Montevideo, Uruguay, 1966. (3 copies) 3) Anderson, H. Calvert. "The ABC Communication Team." (folder) Montevideo, Uruguay, 1966. (in Spanish, 3 copies) 4) Anderson, H. Calvert. "Agricultural Communications in Latin America." Paper prepared for delivery at the International Congress of Farm Writers, Montreal, Canada, June 21, 1967. 5a-b) Anderson, H. Calvert. "Agricultural Information in Southern Brazil: A Situation Study with Recommendations for Cooperative Training Programs." Montevideo, Uruguay, 1964. 6) Anderson, H. Calvert. "Agricultural Information in Southern Brazil: A Situation Study with Recommendations for Cooperative Training Programs." Montevideo, Uruguay, 1964. (in Portuguese) 7) Anderson, H. Calvert. "Communications and Agrarian Reform." Montevideo, Uruguay, 1964. (3 copies) 8) Anderson, H. Calvert. "Communications and Agrarian Reform." Montevideo, Uruguay, 1964. (in Spanish, 3 copies) 9) Anderson, H. Calvert. "Communications Training, A Chain Reaction." Montevideo, Uruguay, 1965. (3 copies)
  - Inter-American Popular Information Program (PIIP) - Publications #10-13 (Box 68, Folder 479)
    10) Anderson, H. Calvert. "Creando Uno Oficina de Informatión." Montevideo, Uruguay, 1964. (3 copies) 11) Anderson, H. Calvert. "Información: Argentina, Bolivia, Brasil, Paraguay, Perú y Uruguay." Montevideo, Uruguay, 1963. (3 copies) 12) Anderson, H. Calvert. "Establecimiento de Una Oficina Técnica de Informatión Agrícola." La Paz, Bolivia: Ministerio de Agricultura, 1967. 13) Anderson, H. Calvert. "Planificación y Presentación de Cursos Cortos de comunicación." Montevideo, Uruguay, 1966. (3 copies)
  - Inter-American Popular Information Program (PIIP) - Publications #14-16 (Box 69, Folder 480)
    14a-b) Anderson, H. Calvert. "Planificación y Presentación de Cursos Cortos de comunicación." Montevideo, Uruguay, 1967. (reprint in English, 3 copies) 15) Anderson, H. Calvert. (ed.) "Research in Actino for the Economic Development of Uruguay." Agricultural Research Center of the Ministry of Livestock and Agriculture in Uruguay. Translated by Yvonne Bourdette. Montevideo, Uruguay, 1967. (3 copies) 16) Anderson, H. Calvert. "The Role of Communications in Agricultural Development." Montevideo, Uruguay, 1965.
  - Inter-American Popular Information Program (PIIP) - Publications #17-18 (Box 69, Folder 481)
    17a-c) Anderson, H. Calvert y Carlos A. Prato Blume. "Manual de Operaciones para Una Oficina de Información Agrícola" - Partes I, II, III. Ministerio de Agricultura. Lima, Perú, 1964. (2 copies of 1, 3 copies of b) 18) Anderson, H. Calvert y Eduardo Pereira Brum. "Plan para Un Servico de Información para el Centro de Investigaciones Agrícolas Alberto Boerger, La Estanzuela, Uruguay." Montevideo, Uruguay, 1964.
  - Inter-American Popular Information Program (PIIP) - Publications #19-21 (Box 69, Folder 482)
    19) Arce, Antonio M. A. "A Study of the Human and Institutional Resources in the Social Sciences and Communications Research in Selected Countries in Latin America." San José, Costa Rica: Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences, 1961. (3 copies) 20) Arce, Antonio M. A. "A Study of the Human and Institutional Resources in the Social Sciences and Communications Research in Selected Countries in Latin America." San José, Costa Rica: Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences, 1961. (in Spanish) 21) Arce, Eduardo Tironi. "Visión Panorámica de la Television Educativa." Lima, Peru: Oficina Técnica de Informatión Agraria. Ministerio de Agricultura, 1965.
  - Inter-American Popular Information Program (PIIP) - Publication #22 - "Campañas Educativas." Producidas durante el Curso Básico de Adiestramiento en Comunicaciones. Montevideo, Uruguay, 1962. (Box 69, Folder 483)
  - Inter-American Popular Information Program (PIIP) - Publication #23 - Chile. Ministerio de Agricultura e Instituto Interamericano de Ciencias Agrícolas. "Seminario: El Palel del la Comunicación en el Desarrollo Económico." Santiago Miscelanea No. 11. Ed. Raúl e. Torres Ramos. 1965. (Box 69, Folder 484)
  - Inter-American Popular Information Program (PIIP) - Publications #24a-v - "Comuniquémonos.", 1964-1967 (Box 69, Folder 485)
    Newsletter distributed bimonthly to communications specialists throughout Latin America from Montevideo, Uruguay. 2 copies of August 1966, 3 copies of June 1967
  - Inter-American Popular Information Program (PIIP) - Publications #25-29 (Box 70, Folder 486)
    25) Costa Rica. Misión de Operaciones de los Estados Unidos. Administración de Cooperación Internacional y Instituto Interamericano de Ciencias Agricolas. "Fotografia Educativa." La edición y traducción de loas artículos del ingles al español escritos por Mario M. Vásquez. 26) Deutschmann, Paul. "A Machine Simulation of Attitude Change in a Polarized Community." San José, Costa Rica, 1962. (3 copies) 27) Deutschmann, Paul. "A Machine Simulation of Information Diffusion in a Small Community." San José, Costa Rica, 1962. (2 copies) 28) Deutschmann, Paul. "The Mass Media in an Underdeveloped Village." "Journalism Quarterly." Vol. 40, No. 1 - Winter 1963. 29) Deutschmann, Paul and Orlando Fals-Borda. "Communication Among Colombian Peasants." Monografías Sociológicas No. 14. Universidad Nacional de Columbia. 1962. (Also in Spanish)
  - Inter-American Popular Information Program (PIIP) - Publications #30-33 (Box 70, Folder 487)
    30) Deutschmann, Paul and Orlando Fals-Borda. "Communication and Adoption Patterns in an Andean Village." San José, Costa Rica: Universidad Nacional de Columbia. 1962. 31) Deutschmann, Paul and Orlando Fals-Borda. "Communication in an Andean Village." Presented at the Convention of the Association for Education in Journalism. University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, 1962. (Also in Spanish, 3 copies) 32) Deutschmann, Paul and John T. McNelly. "El Uso de Los Medios de Comunicación Masiva en Dos Comunidades Latinoamericanas." Presentado en el XIII Congreso Nacional de Sociología, Hermosillo, Sonora, México, 1962. (2 copies) 33) Deutschmann, Paul and Alfredo Méndez. "A Preliminary Report on Perception of Hot and Cold Foods in Two Villages." San José, Costa Rica: Instituto de Nutrición de Centro América y Panamá, 1963. (3 copies)
  - Inter-American Popular Information Program (PIIP) - Publications #34-35 (Box 70, Folder 488)
    34) Deutschmann, Paul, Alfredo Méndez and William Herzog. "Adoption of Drugs and Foods in Five Guatemalan Villages." San José, Costa Rica: Instituto de Nutrición de Centro América y Panamá, 1967. (3 copies) 35) Díaz Bordenave, Juan, Antonio M. Arce and John T. McNelly. "Three Preliminary Biblographies of Works Related to the Social Sciences in Latin America." San José, Costa Rica, 1967. (English and Spanish in one publication, 3 copies)
  - Inter-American Popular Information Program (PIIP) - Publications #36-39 (Box 70, Folder 489)
    36) Díaz Bordenave, Juan y Frederick B. Waisanen. "What is Communication Research?" San José, Costa Rica: Scientific Communication Service of the Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences, 1965. (Also in Spanish) 37) Fonseca, Luiz, and William R. Lassey. "Comprehension and Meaning in Visual Communication Among Illiterate, Low Literate and Higher Literate Individuals." (preliminary report). San José, Costa Rica: Scientific Communications Service of the Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences, 1964. 38) "Impact Training." Montevideo, Uruguay, 1963. (2 copies) 39) Instituto Interamericano de Ciencias Agrícolas. "Como Escribir para Educar al Agricultor." Resumen informativo del Curso Internacional de Comunicación Escrita. Montevideo, Uruguay, 1963. (3 copies)
  - Inter-American Popular Information Program (PIIP) - Publication #40 - Instituto Interamericano de Ciencias Agrícola." Montevideo, Uruguay, 1963., 2 copies (Box 70, Folder 490)
  - Inter-American Popular Information Program (PIIP) - Publications #41-45 (Box 70, Folder 491)
    41) Instituto Interamericano de Ciencias Agrícolas. "Curso en: Comunicaciones para Personal de Servicos de Información." (Under contract between the Institute and the US Agency for International Development.) Montevideo, Uruguay, 1962. 42) Instituto Nacional de Tecnología Agropecuario. "Estudio de la Prensa del Interior de la República Argentina." Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1966 (3 copies) 43) Instituto Nacional de Tecnología Agropecuario. "Estudio de la Prensa del Interior de la República Argentina." Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1966 (profile in English, 3 copies) 44) Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences. "Better Communications: Report of Basic Course in Communications." Montevideo, Uruguay, 1962. (2 copies) 45) Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences. "Better Communications: Report of Basic Course in Communications." Montevideo, Uruguay, 1962. (in Spanish)
  - Inter-American Popular Information Program (PIIP) - Publication #46 - "Manual de Comunicaciones." San José, Costa Rica, 1962 (Box 70, Folder 492)
  - Inter-American Popular Information Program (PIIP) - Publications #47-51 (Box 71, Folder 493)
    47) McNelly, John T. and Augusto Torres. "A Study of the Use of the Mass Media and Knowledge of Current Affairs as Related to Socioeconomic Status in San José." Paper presented at the Convention of the Association for Education in Journalism. University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, 1962. (2 copies) 48) McNelly, John T. "El Uso de Los Medios de Comunicación en Una Capital Latinoamericana." San José, Costa Rica, 1963. (3 copies) 49) Méndez, Alfredo, and Frederick B. Waisanen. "Some Correlates of Functional Literacy." Instituto de Nutrición de Centro América y Panamá. Paper prepared for the Inter-American Congress of Psychology. Miami, 1964. (Also in Spanish, 3 copies) 50) Perú. Ministerio de Agricultura. Oficina Técnica de Información Agraria. "Manual de Operaciones." Basado en "Manual de Operaciones para una Oficina de Información Agrícola" por H. Calvert Anderson (PIIP) y Carlos A. Prato Blume (Ministerio de Agricultura) Lima, Peru, 1964. 51) "Twelve Months Report (1958-1959)." San José, Costa Rica. (3 copies)
  - Inter-American Popular Information Program (PIIP) - Publications #52-59 (Box 71, Folder 494)
    52) Uruguay, Ministerio de Ganadería y Agricultura. Centro Nacional de Extensión Agropecuaria. Centrol de Investigaciones Agrícolas Alberto Boerger. "La Prensa del Interior del Uruguay." Montevideo, Uruguay, 1966. (3 copies) 53) Uruguay, Ministerio de Ganadería y Agricultura. Centro Nacional de Extensión Agropecuaria. Centrol de Investigaciones Agrícolas Alberto Boerger. "La Prensa del Interior del Uruguay." Montevideo, Uruguay, 1966. (English supplement, 3 copies) 54) Waisanen, Frederick B. "Aspects of the Adoption Process." San José, Costa, Rica, 1963. (3 copies) 55) Waisanen, Frederick B. "Change, Orientation and the Adoption Process." San José, Costa Rica, 1964. (also in Spanish) 56) Waisanen, Frederick B. "Communication Flow to Traditional Social Systems." San José, Costa Rica, 1963. (3 copies) 57) Waisanen, Frederick B. "Social Sciences: Problems and Prospects." San José, Costa Rica, 1963. (3 copies) 58) Wasianen, Frederick B. "Social Sciences: Problems and Prospects." San José, Costa Rica, 1963. (in Spanish, 3 copies) 59) Waisanen, Frederick B. "A Symbolic Interactionistic Approach to Communication and Change." San José, Costa Rica, 1963. (3 copies)
  - Inter-American Rural Development Program (PIDR) - Publication #1 - Brazil, Estado de Minas Gerias. Secretário da Agricultura. "Colonization Plan: Land Reform Program of the State of Minas Gerais" Belo Horizonte, 1961 (Box 71, Folder 495)
  - Inter-American Rural Development Program (PIDR) - Publications #2-4 (Box 71, Folder 496)
    2) Brazilian National Research Council. "Coordinated Research Program in Camp Cerrado Areas of Brazil." Translated by Walter Crawford and Lawrence Witt. Rio de Janeiro, 1966. (3 copies) 3) Brazilian National Research Council. "Coordinated Research Program in Campo Cerrado Areas of Brazil." Translated by Walter Crawford and Lawrence Witt, Rio de Janeiro, 1966. (in Portuguese, 3 copies) 4) Crawford, Walter L. "Colonization in Paraguay." (a confidential report) Asunción, 1964. (3 copies)
  - Inter-American Rural Development Program (PIDR) - Publications #5-7 (Box 71, Folder 497)
    5) Crawford, Walter L. "Producción y Crédito Agrícola en el Paraguay." Asunción, 1963. 6) Crawford, Walter L. "Producción y Crédito Agrícola en el Paraguay." Asunción, 1963. (in English) 7) Crawford, Walter L. and others. "Preliminary Report of the Planalto Pre-Survey Group." Prepared under contract for the US Agency for International Development. Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 1963. (3 copies)
  - Inter-American Rural Development Program (PIDR) - Publication #8 - Crawford, Walter L. and others. "Survey of the Agricultural Potential of the Central Plateau of Brazil." Prepared under contract for the US Agency for International Development. Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 1963, 3 copies (Box 72, Folder 498)
  - Inter-American Rural Development Program (PIDR) - Publication #9 - Crawford, Walter L. and others. "Survey of the Agricultural Potential of the Central Plateau of Brazil." Prepared under contract for the US Agency for International Development. Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 1963, 3 copies (Box 72, Folder 499)
  - Inter-American Rural Development Program (PIDR) - Publications #10-12 (Box 72, Folder 500)
    10) Fundação Antunes. "Possibilidades de Desenvolvimento Rural Nos Municipos de Campos e São João da Barra." (Preliminary Study). Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 1965. 11) Heaton, Louis E., Walter L. Crawford and John R. Camp. "Rural Development in Latin America." New York, 1963. (3 copies) 12) Montero, Emilio. "Colonization Plan of the State of Minas Gerais, Brazil: Size of Economic Unit in Jaíba, Minas Gerais." Belo Horizonte. Minas Gerais: Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences, 1962.
  - Inter-American Rural Development Program (PIDR) - Publication #13 - Tosi, Jr., Joseph A. "Reconnaissance Ecological and Forest Survey of the Jaíba Colonization Area. State of Minas Gerais, Brazil." Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais: Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Scienes, 1962. (Box 72, Folder 501)
  - Inter-American Rural Youth Program (PIJR) - Publications #1-6 (Box 72, Folder 502)
    1) "Announcement of PIJR Awards." (pamphlet) San José, Costa Rica, 1967. (3 copies) 2) "Announcement of PIJR Awards." (pamphlet) San José, Costa Rica, 1967. (in Spanish, 3 copies) 3a-d) "Boletín Informativo Tremestral Juventud Rural." José, Costa Rica, 1967. (3 copies) 4a-d) "Boletín Informativo Tremestral Juventud Rural." San José, Costa Rica, 1966. (3 copies) 5) Flamm, Gerald. "Your Publicity Program." San José, Costa Rica, 1965. (3 copies) 6) Flamm, Gerald. "Your Publicity Program." San José, Costa Rica, 1965. (in Spanish, revised 1967, 3 copies)
  - Inter-American Rural Youth Program (PIJR) - Publications #7a-gg - Ford Motor Company. "Juventud Rural." (bulletins issued quarterly, also in English and Portuguese). Dearborn, Michigan, 1962, 1963, 1964, 8 issues duplicated (Box 72, Folder 503)
  - Inter-American Rural Youth Program (PIJR) - Publications #8-11 (Box 72, Folder 504)
    8) Ford Motor Company. "Rural Youth in the Americas." San José, Costa Rica, 1965. (3 copies) 9) Ford Motor Company. "Rural Youth in the Americas." San José, Costa Rica, 1965. (in Spanish, 3 copies) 10) "Guía Para Líderes Juveniles." Translation of "Guide for Junior Leaders," "National 4-H News." San José, Costa Rica, 1967. 11) "Informe de la IV Reunión Nacional de Líderes Estatales de Clubes 4-S." Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 1963. (3 copies)
  - Inter-American Rural Youth Program (PIJR) - Publication #12 - "Informe del Seminaro Interamericano de Líderes de Juventudes Rurales (IFYE)." San José, Costa Rica, 1961, 3 copies (Box 72, Folder 505)
  - Inter-American Rural Youth Program (PIJR) - Publication #13 - "Planes Individuales de Trabajo." Seminarios Interamericano de Líderes de Juventudes Rurales. San José, Costa Rica, 1961 (Box 73, Folder 506)
  - Inter-American Rural Youth Program (PIJR) - Publication #14 - "Informe de la IV Reunión Nacional de Líderes Estatales de Clubes 4-S." Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 1962., 2 copies (Box 73, Folder 507)
  - Inter-American Rural Youth Program (PIJR) - Publication #15 - "Informe del Tercer Seminaro Interamericano de Líderes de Juventudes Rurales (IFYE)." San José, Costa Rica, 1963 (Box 73, Folder 508)
  - Inter-American Rural Youth Program (PIJR) - Publication #16 - Instituto Interamericano de Ciencias Agrícolas. "Taller Interamericano Educativo Sobre Programas de Juventudes Rurales." Turrialba, Costa Rica, 1960 (Box 73, Folder 509)
  - Inter-American Rural Youth Program (PIJR) - Publication #17 - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences. "Report of the Inter-American Rural Youth Program Advisory Meeting." San José, Costa Rica, 1961 (Box 73, Folder 510)
    In Spanish.
  - Inter-American Rural Youth Program (PIJR) - Publications #18-21 (Box 73, Folder 511)
    18) Jones, Earl. "A Study of Rural Youth Programs in The Americas (except United States and Canada)." Ph.D. thesis submitted to Montana State College. Publication prepared under provisions of contact between the Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences and the US Agency for International Development. Turriba, Costa Rica, 1962. 19) Jones, Earl. "Summary of a Study of Rural Youth Programs in the Americas." San José, Costa Rica, 1962. (2 copies) 20) Jones, Earl. "Summary of a Study of Rural Youth Programs in the Americas." San José, Costa Rica, 1962. (in Spanish, 3 copies) 21) Jones, Earl. "Summary of a Study of Rural Youth Programs in the Americas." San José, Costa Rica, 1962. (in Portuguese)
  - Inter-American Rural Youth Program (PIJR) - Publications #22-23 (Box 73, Folder 512)
    22) Jones, Earl. Howard Law and Manuel Valverde. "Preliminary Report: Study of the Rural Youth Programs in the Americas." Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences. San José, Costa Rica, 1961. 23) Jones, Earl, Howard Law and Manuel Valverde. "Preliminary Report: Study of the Rural Youth Program sin the Americas." Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences. San José, Costa Rica, 1961. (in Spanish)